<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title></title>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://0xkafkaa.com/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://0xkafkaa.com/"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2026-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://0xkafkaa.com/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>The End of Loneliness</title>
        <published>2026-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2026-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              0xkafkaa
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/the-end-of-loneliness/"/>
        <id>https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/the-end-of-loneliness/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/the-end-of-loneliness/">&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;img&#x2F;blogs&#x2F;endofloneliness.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Book&quot;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of late, there has been a quiet thought sitting at the back of my head that I haven’t completed a single book this year. One reason being most of the books I tried reading didn’t excite me as much as I thought they would, so I was obliged to drop them midway and thus began my reading slump. But during Christmas Eve, I stumbled upon ‘The End of Loneliness’ by sheer serendipity, began reading it on a whim, and it etched a mark that lingered long after I turned the final page.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘The End of Loneliness’ by Benedict Wells is a German book about Jules Moreau and his fractured life and his pursuit through it while never losing hope. The book reminds us of a truth we often choose to ignore. We wildly overestimate the time we are going to be spending on this planet but we might never know what the future holds and that could be a tough pill to swallow. The future feels infinite—until it isn’t. And that realization is not an easy one to sit with.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dynamics between a father and a son have always bewildered me. The grief Jules goes through after the loss of his parents during his childhood, I couldn’t even find the words to describe the emotions, the agony he goes through and how, once vivacious and fearless, Jules retreats inward, preferring to live within his memories.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is something profoundly comforting about words. It is that they continue to exist between pages for all eternity untouched by time. Through them, characters like Jules end up being immortal. Not every story ends with a ‘they lived happily ever after’ and they never have to be because &lt;em&gt;Life is not a zero-sum game. It owes us nothing, and things just happen the way they do. Sometimes they’re fair and everything makes sense; sometimes they’re so unfair we question everything. I pulled the mask off the face of Fate, and all I found beneath it was chance.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>On Not Belonging</title>
        <published>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              0xkafkaa
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/on-not-belonging/"/>
        <id>https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/on-not-belonging/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/on-not-belonging/">&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;img&#x2F;blogs&#x2F;onBelonging.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nighthawks by Edward Hopper&quot;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
Its been two years on this perky little place on the internet. 
&lt;p&gt;When I started this site, I honestly had no clue about where it would lead me to. But I always felt like I never belonged anywhere. I never really liked the traditional social media or the &lt;em&gt;enshitification&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; of those platforms in general. Trying to be visible admist a plethora of voices never made sense to be anyway. That might be one of the key reasons for building this perky litte digital nest.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never really cared whether people read my writing and I still don’t. But the innate need for validation as a social being, stemming from our human nature brought about by the evolutionary advantage of belonging to a group could be one of the reasons I still might want people to read it. I know I’m contradicting myself, but I don’t really care. Maybe it’s just a paradox of expression. It’s your choice to read on, or not. With the diminishing attention span day after day, I doubt anyone’s reading this anyway.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To live in a hype-chasing reality where the brightest brains of our generation are working on making people watch ads - could be the tragedy of incentives. It’s not that the tech is bad - it’s just that it’s misaligned with deeper human aspirations. Most of the cool products which are being built today are nothing but fancy LLM wrappers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do embrace LLM - nothing against them, also I do enjoy vibe coding, would continue to do so as well. It might sound idiosyncratic but the level of abstraction we have achieved in computing right now kinda makes me eerie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m trying to find answers to questions that would never mount to anything. This petit piece of writing is as well one such quest, born from a simple thought I had - i.e about being mediocre layered with a impostor enhancement syndrome.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people know ‘Vincent van Gogh’, some people love his paintings. But I, on the other hand, admire van Gogh for his writings. Here are a few lines from his letters:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I would like to leave this world and never return. I severed my ear, but how I wish that I had severed my heart. I shall never amount to anything.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In spite of everything, I shall rise again.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What am I in the eyes of most people? A non-entity or an eccentric and a disagreeable man. I should want my work to show what is in the heart of such an eccentric, of such a nobody.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“My opinion is that the best thing would be to work on till art lovers feel drawn towards it of their own accord, instead of having to praise or to explain it.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if you get it. But van Gogh was right all along. Being mediocre, lost, and eccentric is all just part of the process. Even though he didn’t live to experience all the love his work would eventually receive, he was right all along.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>On Keeping a Notebook</title>
        <published>2025-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              0xkafkaa
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/on-keeping-a-notebook/"/>
        <id>https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/on-keeping-a-notebook/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/on-keeping-a-notebook/">&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;img&#x2F;blogs&#x2F;writing.png&quot; alt=&quot;notebooks&quot;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point of my keeping a notebook has never been, nor is it now, to have an accurate factual record of what I have been doing or thinking. That would be a different impulse entirely, an instinct for reality which I sometimes envy but do not possess. At no point have I ever been able successfully to keep a diary; my approach to daily life ranges from the grossly negligent to the merely absent, and on those few occasions when I have tried dutifully to record a day’s events, boredom has so overcome me that the results are mysterious at best.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keepers of private notebooks are a different breed altogether, lonely and resistant rearrangers of things, anxious malcontents, children afflicted apparently at birth with some presentiment of loss.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sometimes delude myself about why I keep a notebook, imagine that some thrifty virtue derives from preserving everything observed. See enough and write it down, I tell myself, and then some morning when the world seems drained of wonder, some day when I am only going through the motions of doing what I am supposed to do, which is write - on that bankrupt morning I will simply open my notebook and there it will all be, a forgotten account with accumulated interest, paid passage back to the world out there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above content is from Slouching Towads Bethlehem by Joan Didion.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been writing things down since I was 13 years old but I’ve never really understood the true reason why I started writing. I wrote stuff down simply because I felt an urge to etch those words somewhere for some reason. Though some of it were lost during the years, a certain few remains. They evoke a part of me that’s no longer alive. Now I am in my 20s, I still keep a collection of notebooks for various topics. Yes, I hoard notebooks, yet I enjoy the process of putting pen to paper.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write things down, not as an account of remembrance, but simply as an act of writing. Even if you don’t get anything out of it, over time, you will come to appreciate the art of writing. Keep your notebooks messy, it doesn’t have to be in order and not everything has to make sense. In due time you will find order in those chaos. With the advent of an AI first approach towads everything, in a few years, writing might even become one of the few ways to truly feel human. Always keep a notebook, commute with it, eat with it and slap every stray thought in it. Just keep writing, every day, even if its just a word or two, it all adds up in the end.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Building Suttakural - A fun little project</title>
        <published>2025-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              0xkafkaa
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/building-suttakural/"/>
        <id>https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/building-suttakural/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/building-suttakural/">&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;img&#x2F;blogs&#x2F;suttakural.png&quot; alt=&quot;suttakural web UI&quot;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens when you mix ancient wisdom with modern sarcasm?
So, ever since I had a look at this &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;datasets&#x2F;Selvakumarduraipandian&#x2F;Thirukural&quot;&gt;Thirukural dataset&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; I wanted to build something with it, that’s when a simple thought: What if Thiruvalluvar could roast people based on their thoughts? Hence &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;suttakural.kafkaa.xyz&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Suttakural&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; was born - a webapp that roasts you using Thirukural, blending Valluvar’s wisdom with AI-generated burns.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stack is actually simple, the client sends a query to an LLM and the LLM picks up a relavant Thirukural and generates a bunch of roasts and later they are rendered in the frontend. Sounds simple right but I don’t wanna do it this way primarily because of two reasons firstly, its boring and secondly, I don’t wanna spend anything on acquiring an API key and also the roasts from Gemini are so lifeless.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s when I decided to do this the hard way which is to generate the roasts beforehand using an LLM. I crafted a bunch of tailered prompts and got the data I needed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;json&quot; class=&quot;language-json &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-json&quot; data-lang=&quot;json&quot;&gt;{
  &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: 928,
  &amp;quot;kural_tamil&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;களிததறியேன எனபது கைவிடுக நெஞசதது\nஒளிதததூஉம ஆஙகே மிகும.&amp;quot;,
  &amp;quot;kural_english&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;No more in secret drink, and then deny thy hidden fraud; What in thy mind lies hid shall soon be known abroad.&amp;quot;,
  &amp;quot;theme&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Secrets and Lies&amp;quot;,
  &amp;quot;roasts&amp;quot;: {
    &amp;quot;1&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;You think no one knows? Bro, even your bottle is judging you harder than your conscience.&amp;quot;,
    &amp;quot;2&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Stop pretending, your secrets are spilling out like your last drunk confession. We see it all.&amp;quot;,
    &amp;quot;3&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;The only thing hidden is your shame, and trust me, that’s coming out faster than you can cover it up.&amp;quot;,
    &amp;quot;4&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;You can lie about your drinking all you want, but the truth is already public knowledge, bro.&amp;quot;,
    &amp;quot;5&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;You’ve mastered the art of deceit — but the only thing you’re hiding now is the inevitable humiliation.&amp;quot;
  }
}
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I pushed them into a vector DB with the vector embeddings generated for the roasts using a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;huggingface.co&#x2F;sentence-transformers&#x2F;all-MiniLM-L6-v2&quot;&gt;Sentence Transformer model&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; - it maps sentences &amp;amp; paragraphs to a 384 dimensional dense vector space and can be used for tasks like clustering or semantic search.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then spun up a fastapi backend which sends a query to the vector DB and does a semantic search and retrieves the result which is later rendered in the frontend.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, everything works the way I wanted it to be. Not its ready to be deployed and I was in a notion that is should be pretty easy. But here is where I spent so much time troubleshooting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;img&#x2F;blogs&#x2F;sk-arch.png&quot; alt=&quot;suttakural arch&quot;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I ususally deploy by projects in my server as I have mentioned in the earlier blogs. But one problem was the Docker image of the backend was pretty huge and I know it should not be this case. Since I was using an ML model for generating text embeddings, it downloads a bunch of dependencies which I don’t need to begin with and I haven’t worked on ML models, so I had no clue whether this was normal. After a night of scouring the internet I understood how to make use of only the dependencies I need and finally reduced the size of the image. And now the backend is up and running.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next hassle was with configuring the reverse proxy and I use Caddy as my reverse proxy, by the way. So, if you are not aware, Caddy automatically obtains and renews TLS certificates for all your sites by default. But for some reason my backend was running only in &lt;em&gt;http&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and it needs to be running in &lt;em&gt;https&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; to connect to the frontend. I wasn’t able to piece them together.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried a bunch of troubleshooting and even manually assigned the TLS certificates but nothing seemed to be working. But later found, I was making a dumb mistake. Reverse proxies should not be exposing the port in which the application is running, instead it should route traffic securely while keeping backend services hidden. But I was able to access the backend with my server IP tagged with the port running the application. So, the issue was I was binding the port of the backend to all interfaces with 0.0.0.0 instead of the localhost 127.0.0.1. Once I corrected this, everything worked as expected.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here you go. &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;suttakural.kafkaa.xyz&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Suttakural&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; - a web app that roasts you using Thirukkural, blending Thiruvalluvar’s wisdom with AI-generated burns.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Exploring Microcontrollers</title>
        <published>2025-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              0xkafkaa
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/exploring-microcontrollers/"/>
        <id>https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/exploring-microcontrollers/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/exploring-microcontrollers/">&lt;p&gt;I have always been curious about Microcontrollers and IOT in general ever since I got interested in the hacking culture. The beauty of the computation which happens in a cute litte component always makes me appreciate it further more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;img&#x2F;blogs&#x2F;mc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;microcontroller&quot;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;UrbanCircles&#x2F;igor&quot;&gt;Project IGOR&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;@UrbanCircles&quot;&gt;Urban Circles&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; felt like a great place to start. In a world full of distractions, build with overly engineered products for productivy finding something which does only one simple task could be challenging. This is what &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;UrbanCircles&#x2F;igor&quot;&gt;Project IGOR&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; tries to solve. I just love the philosophy on which its built on.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&quot;Do one thing and do it well.&quot;
- Doug McIlroy
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;UrbanCircles&#x2F;igor&quot;&gt;Project IGOR&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, an open-source focus timer project using an ESP8266, an OLED display, and a rotary encoder. Igor is designed to provide an intuitive way to manage focus sessions. The rotary encoder is used to set the time, and the OLED display provides real-time feedback. The ESP8266 acts as the brain of the system, handling user inputs and updating the display.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The firmware is written in Arduino using the Adafruit SSD1306 and Rotary Encoder libraries. The main logic involves:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading the rotary encoder to adjust the timer.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Displaying the timer on the OLED screen.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starting a countdown and updating the display.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Triggering an alert or indication when the session ends.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I messed up a few components during soldering them since I am all new to this but it was a fun little project. Implementing Igor was an exciting journey into embedded development, combining hardware interfacing, real-time input handling, and display manipulation.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Bookmark Management with Linkding: A Self-Hosted Guide</title>
        <published>2025-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              0xkafkaa
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/selfhosting-a-bookmark-manager/"/>
        <id>https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/selfhosting-a-bookmark-manager/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/selfhosting-a-bookmark-manager/">&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;img&#x2F;blogs&#x2F;linkding.webp&quot; alt=&quot;linking ui&quot;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet offers a wealth of resources, but only a handful truly grab our attention. Sadly, these gems often vanish into the vast web abyss if not carefully bookmarked. Personally, I’ve relied on my browser’s bookmarks folder for years. While convenient, searching through this growing list often becomes an arduous task.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I previously used &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;omnivore.app&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Omnivore&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a “read it later” application, until it shut down last year. This led me to explore bookmark managers. Although I found plenty of great options like &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.are.na&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Are.na&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;hoarder.app&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Hoarder&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;linkwarden.app&quot;&gt;Linkwarden&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the one that truly caught my eye was &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;linkding.link&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Linkding&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Its simplicity stood out, and since adopting it, managing my bookmarks has been a seamless experience.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog, I’ll walk you through how to set up Linkding on your own server.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;setting-up-linkding&quot;&gt;Setting Up Linkding&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The setup is straightforward if you follow the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;linkding.link&#x2F;installation&#x2F;&quot;&gt;official documentation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. All you need is a simple Docker Compose configuration. Below is an example:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot; class=&quot;language-yaml &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;services:
  linkding:
    container_name: &amp;quot;${LD_CONTAINER_NAME:-linkding}&amp;quot;
    image: sissbruecker&amp;#x2F;linkding:latest
    ports:
      - &amp;quot;${LD_HOST_PORT:-9090}:9090&amp;quot;
    volumes:
      - &amp;quot;${LD_HOST_DATA_DIR:-.&amp;#x2F;data}:&amp;#x2F;etc&amp;#x2F;linkding&amp;#x2F;data&amp;quot;
    env_file:
      - .env
    restart: unless-stopped
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating-a-superuser&quot;&gt;Creating a Superuser&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create a superuser, you can use the following command while the container is running:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;bash&quot; class=&quot;language-bash &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;docker exec -it linkding python manage.py createsuperuser --username=joe --email=joe@example.com
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, define the superuser credentials in the &lt;code&gt;.env&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; file:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;env&quot; class=&quot;language-env &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-env&quot; data-lang=&quot;env&quot;&gt;LD_SUPERUSER_NAME=myusername
LD_SUPERUSER_PASSWORD=mypassword
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;accessing-the-ui&quot;&gt;Accessing the UI&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once your container is running, you can access the Linkding UI at &lt;strong&gt;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;localhost:9090&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Log in using the credentials you set up, and you’re good to go! Additionally, you can install the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;chromewebstore.google.com&#x2F;detail&#x2F;linkding-extension&#x2F;beakmhbijpdhipnjhnclmhgjlddhidpe&quot;&gt;Linkding browser extension&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to start saving links effortlessly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;enhancing-linkding-with-add-ons&quot;&gt;Enhancing Linkding with Add-Ons&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;linkding-injector&quot;&gt;Linkding Injector&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;img&#x2F;blogs&#x2F;linkding-inj.webp&quot; alt=&quot;linking ui&quot;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;Fivefold&#x2F;linkding-injector&quot;&gt;Linkding Injector&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a browser extension that displays your saved bookmarks directly in your search engine results. It’s easy to set up by following the instructions in the repository.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;mobile-integration-with-http-shortcuts&quot;&gt;Mobile Integration with HTTP Shortcuts&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you frequently use your mobile to save links, Linkding has you covered! Install the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;f-droid.org&#x2F;packages&#x2F;ch.rmy.android.http_shortcuts&#x2F;&quot;&gt;HTTP Shortcuts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; app from F-Droid. Here’s how to set it up:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open the app and go to the three-dot menu in the top-right corner.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select &lt;strong&gt;Import&#x2F;Export&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, then choose &lt;strong&gt;Import from URL&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter this URL:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;raw.githubusercontent.com&amp;#x2F;sissbruecker&amp;#x2F;linkding&amp;#x2F;refs&amp;#x2F;heads&amp;#x2F;master&amp;#x2F;docs&amp;#x2F;src&amp;#x2F;assets&amp;#x2F;linkding_shortcut.json
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After importing, go back to the main screen, open the three-dot menu again, and select &lt;strong&gt;Variables&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update the &lt;strong&gt;linkding_instance&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;linkding_api_key&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; variables with your self-hosted instance details.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, when you share a link from your browser, choose &lt;strong&gt;HTTP Shortcuts&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, select &lt;strong&gt;Linkding&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, and optionally add tags or save it as untagged.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;backing-up-your-bookmarks&quot;&gt;Backing Up Your Bookmarks&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backups are essential for any server. You can automate this process using a shell script and a cronjob. The following commands create a backup of your Linkding database:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;bash&quot; class=&quot;language-bash &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;docker exec -it linkding python manage.py full_backup &amp;#x2F;etc&amp;#x2F;linkding&amp;#x2F;data&amp;#x2F;backup.zip
docker cp linkding:&amp;#x2F;etc&amp;#x2F;linkding&amp;#x2F;data&amp;#x2F;backup.zip backup.zip
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schedule this as a cronjob to ensure your data is always safe.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linkding offers a simple, efficient, and self-hosted solution for bookmark management. From its intuitive UI to useful extensions and mobile integrations, it’s a tool that enhances the way you save and organize your favorite online resources. With regular backups in place, you can rest assured that your bookmarks are safe and accessible whenever you need them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Setting up my VPS</title>
        <published>2024-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              0xkafkaa
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/setting-up-a-vps/"/>
        <id>https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/setting-up-a-vps/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/setting-up-a-vps/">&lt;p&gt;Finally after a year of tinkering with Linux I got myself a &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Virtual_private_server&quot;&gt;Virtual Private Server&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. In this blog post, I would like to list the things I have done after getting a server.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;img&#x2F;blogs&#x2F;server.png&quot; alt=&quot;neofetch output&quot;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connect to VPS with SSH&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; - The first step was to connect to the VPS securely using SSH to ensure encrypted communication.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update package lists and Upgrade packages&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; - As with any Linux distro, the first essential business is to make sure the packages are upto date.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Change root password&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; - For added security, I updated the root password to something more complex immediately.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create non-root user&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; - As a best practise to avoid using the root user for day to day operations, I created a new user with sudo privileges.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Login with SSH Key&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; - I setup SSH key based authentication ensuring the future logins doesn’t require password for the new user.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disable Password Login&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; - Once the SSH key is in place, I disabled the password login to prevent unauthorized access&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disable root login&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; - Disabling root login over SSH adds an extra layer of security, ensuring only non-root users can access the server.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update Network and Firewall Policy&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; - I configured the firewall to allow only necessary services (SSH, HTTP&#x2F;HTTPS, etc.), using ufw&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Closed unused ports&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; - Closed the unused ports to minimize potential entry points for attackers.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Install essential tools&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; - Installed a few essential tools like git and tmux to make woking on the server convenient.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s Running on the VPS?
Currently, Kafkaa is running on my VPS, hosted with Caddy as the web server. Caddy makes HTTPS setup incredibly simple, handling certificates automatically.  I’m excited about all the possibilities it opens up for self-hosting and further projects in the upcoming days.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Going Forward</title>
        <published>2024-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              0xkafkaa
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/going-forward/"/>
        <id>https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/going-forward/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/going-forward/">&lt;p&gt;For a past a few years, there exists a chaos in my mind to share my thoughts online. I have never been comfortable with voicing out my thoughts online. That’s also one of the reasons why I stopped using Social Media. Kafkaa belongs to me, I built it from scrach yet I never found solace in it as well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;img&#x2F;blogs&#x2F;gf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Picture of Hayao Miyazaki&quot;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever an idea strikes me regarding a blog or something, I kinda feel insecure and devle into the rabbit hole of overthinking. I always end up questioning myself with the following. Am I knowledgeable enough as the people I look up to in the same space to create something? Am I being true to myself or just doing it for the content? Am I being passionate enough? and the list goes on and on. The mere fact that I didn’t produce anything substantial with my skills is the key reason for all these thoughts.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, it changes now. From here on, Kafkaa will emerge as a space I always envisioned. I don’t care if the blogs I write are mediocre and the projects I make seem to be middling. Its the process, and has always been the process which I loved being in.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of these days, I will be as good as the people I look upto. Even if I don’t quite make it, I won’t feel any remose. I will cherish the process.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not some random motivation rants. I have been working on myself for quite a while now. And I felt that this is the right moment to do this.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
From here on, Kafkaa will emerge as a space I always envisioned.
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes fate is like a small sandstorm that keeps changing directions. You change direction but the sandstorm chases you. You turn again, but the storm adjusts. Over and over you play this out, like some ominous dance with death just before dawn. Why? Because this storm isn’t something that blew in from far away, something that has nothing to do with you. This storm is you. Something inside of you. So all you can do is give in to it, step right inside the storm, closing your eyes and plugging up your ears so the sand doesn’t get in, and walk through it, step by step. There’s no sun there, no moon, no direction, no sense of time. Just fine white sand swirling up into the sky like pulverized bones. That’s the kind of sandstorm you need to imagine.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you really will have to make it through that violent, metaphysical, symbolic storm. No matter how metaphysical or symbolic it might be, make no mistake about it: it will cut through flesh like a thousand razor blades. People will bleed there, and you will bleed too. Hot, red blood. You’ll catch that blood in your hands, your own blood and the blood of others. And once the storm is over you won’t remember how you made it through, how you managed to survive. You won’t even be sure, in fact, whether the storm is really over.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
But one thing is certain. When you come out of the storm you won&#x27;t be the same person who walked in. That&#x27;s what this storm&#x27;s all about.
&lt;p&gt;– Haruki Murakami&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>A month without media consumption</title>
        <published>2024-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              0xkafkaa
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/no-media-consumption/"/>
        <id>https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/no-media-consumption/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/no-media-consumption/">&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I have had a notion to track my life. So, I started to track a few things since January ’24. Up until now my idea was just to track my actions and understand my habits better rather than pushing myself to maintain a streak on the actions. To give you an idea here is the representation of days on which I was reading a book.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;img&#x2F;blogs&#x2F;reading.png&quot;  alt=&quot;Days spent reading&quot;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was probing for something on the Internet, I serendipitously ended up in this &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;manuelmoreale.com&#x2F;without&quot;&gt;blog by Manu&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. To give you a brief, he gives up something for a month like caffine, videogames and then evaluate whether it was something he enjoyed giving up, and try to comprehend if it’s worth leaving it out of his life. It seemed fun and interesting so I decicded to give it a shot.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, for the month of June I decided to give up media cosumption, to narrow it down I decided to stop watching any form of moving images ranging from Youtube videos, Films, TV Series, Documentaries, or any form of Social Media.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though I didn’t fail miserably in this challenge. I managed to refrain from consuming media for the first ten days which is a small win to cherish for and after which I fell into the old patterns.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the key observation during the initial phase was that my screen time drastically dropped from hours to minutes which I didn’t account for while planning. Also, I spent a lot of time reading. Another important thing was utter boredom, I was expecting to be hit by one eventually. Although going through it was kind of horrendous, it rekindled the good old days when I wasn’t connected to the Internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Yaanai Doctor - A journey into the world of Elephant Healing</title>
        <published>2023-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2023-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              0xkafkaa
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/yaanai-doctor/"/>
        <id>https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/yaanai-doctor/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/yaanai-doctor/">&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;img&#x2F;blogs&#x2F;yd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Book of Yannai Doctor&quot;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, during a visit to Panuval bookstore in Chennai, I came across a book by Jeyamohan, an author whose works I hadn’t explored before. While I had never felt a particular fascination for Jeyamohan’s writings, I decided to take a leap of faith and chose to delve into his world. I picked up two of his works, “Iravu” (Nights) and “Yaanai Doctor” (The Elephant Doctor).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&#x27;டாக்டர் நம்ம பசங்க மாதிரி சபிக்கப்பட்ட தலைமொறை இந்தியாவிலே இருந்ததில்லை. அவங்க முன்னாடி இன்னிக்கு நிக்கிறதெல்லாமே வெறும் கட்டவுட்டு மனுஷங்க. லட்சியவாதமோ கனவொ இல்லாத போலி முகங்க. அவங்கள்லாம் ஜஸ்ட் ஜெயிச்சவங்க டாக்டர். திருடியோ மோசடி பண்ணியோ பணமும் புகழும் அதிகாரமும் அடைஞ்சவங்க. அவங்கள முன்னால பாத்துட்டு ஒரு தலைமுறையே ஓடி வந்திட்டிருக்கு. அந்த பசங்க முன்னாடி இந்தா இப்டி ஒரு ஐடியலிஸத்துக்கும் இன்னும் நம்ம சமூகத்திலே எடமிருக்குன்னு சொல்லலாம்னு நினைச்சேன். இன்னும் இங்க காந்தி வாழறதுக்கு ஒரு காலடி மண்ணிருக்குன்னு சொல்லலாம்னு நினைச்சேன். ஒரு பத்துபேரு கவனிச்சாக்கூட போருமே டாக்டர்&#x27;.
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yaanai Doctor” is a novella that introduces us to Dr. V. Krishnamoorthy, who is affectionately known as Dr. K among the people residing in the vicinity. Dr. K is a dedicated professional working tirelessly for the well-being of both captive and wild elephants in Southern India. It’s a story of passion, compassion, and the extraordinary bond between Dr. K and these magnificent creatures.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I immersed myself in the novella, I discovered that while it may not have resonated deeply with me on a personal level, I found myself captivated by the skillful narration and the unique world it unveils.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the standout moments in the novella is when a herd of elephants makes a journey from Mudumalai to Top Slip, seeking medical aid for a calf in their midst. This poignant episode offers a glimpse into the complex relationship between humans and elephants, and the lengths to which individuals like Dr. K go to ensure their welfare.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story is beautifully narrated from the perspective of a Forest Ranger who is determined to help Dr. K gain the recognition he truly deserves. The ranger’s efforts to have Dr. K acknowledged and honored by the public are at the heart of how the narrative unfolds.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yaanai Doctor” takes readers on a remarkable journey through the world of elephant healing and conservation in Southern India. It is a story of devotion, hope, and the profound connection that can exist between humans and the animal kingdom. Jeyamohan’s storytelling prowess shines throughout the novella, offering a unique and heartwarming glimpse into a world that is both enchanting and vital.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my journey of exploring Jeyamohan’s works, “Yaanai Doctor” may not have struck a personal chord, but it certainly left a lasting impression. It is a tribute to the unsung heroes working to protect and care for our wildlife, reminding us of the importance of coexisting with the incredible creatures that share our planet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a penchant for tales of wildlife, compassion, and human-animal relationships, “Yaanai Doctor” is a must-read. It offers a fresh perspective on the wonders of nature and the extraordinary individuals who dedicate their lives to its preservation.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Resurgence through Reading: My Journey with Haruki Murakami and &#x27;Killing Commendatore</title>
        <published>2023-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2023-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              0xkafkaa
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/killing-commendatore/"/>
        <id>https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/killing-commendatore/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://0xkafkaa.com/writings/killing-commendatore/">&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;img&#x2F;blogs&#x2F;kc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Books of Murakami&quot;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still vividly recall the exhilaration and sense of accomplishment that coursed through me when I completed my very first book. It was the work of Haruki Murakami that guided me on this literary journey. Without him, I doubt I would have developed the habit of reading. Everyone has an author who holds a special place in their heart; however, I’m not one to fawn over authors themselves, but rather the content they create. Yet, Murakami’s influence on instilling this reading habit in me makes me feel indebted to him.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“Reading was like an addiction; I read while I ate, on the train, in bed until late at night, in school, where I&#x27;d keep the book hidden so I could read during class. Before long I bought a small stereo and spent all my time in my room, listening to jazz records. But I had almost no desire to talk to anyone about the experience I gained through books and music. I felt happy just being me and no one else. In that sense I could be called a stack-up loner.”
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as abruptly as the reading habit had blossomed in my life, it mysteriously faded away, almost as if it had never existed. I ceased reading and lost all desire to pick up a book. Despite this, I still had a deep passion for purchasing books, naively hoping that my lost reading habit would return someday. Alas, it remained elusive. So there I was, stuck in a reading slump for over eight long months.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m hardly an expert capable of dispensing advice on how to rekindle the reading habit; ultimately, it’s a personal journey that one must navigate themselves. The solution is as simple as deciding to take a trip—if you want to go to Madurai, just go to Madurai. With that in mind, I turned to Murakami once again to help me break free from the reading rut. Unfortunately, I had already devoured most of his major works prior to the slump. It was during this time that I stumbled upon “Killing Commendatore,” a book that would reignite my passion for reading.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon discovering that the protagonist of the book was an artist, I didn’t hesitate for a moment before snatching it up. I was immediately captivated by the unfolding of the story, particularly the portrayal of the nameless artist’s mundane life. However, that’s where my admiration for the book ends. In the past, when I completed a piece of Murakami’s work, I was often left in a state of awe, but “Killing Commendatore” didn’t quite resonate with me. I wouldn’t say that I disliked it, but I found it challenging to fully grasp or connect with, at least from my perspective.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite my mixed feelings towards the book, I’m delighted to report that I’ve successfully emerged from my reading slump, thanks to Murakami’s magic. It’s the first time I’ve felt somewhat disenchanted with his work, but the important thing is that I’m back to enjoying books and reading once again.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
